Shawn Selway

PITTSBURGH, PA | 412.427.7599 SSELWAY@GMAIL.COM

PROFILE

Shawn has over 20+ years of experience in web related technologies of which he has dedicated 10+ years exclusively to SharePoint. As a Senior SharePoint Consultant, he has successfully architected, configured, and deployed dozens of SharePoint 2007/2010/2013/2016/O365 (SharePoint Online) farms. He has also developed numerous PowerShell scripts, custom features, workflows, and utilized third-party components to extend SharePoint OOTB functionality. His experience as a consultant has allowed him to work in a variety of industries including: Fortune 500's, Law, Insurance, Energy, Big Pharma, and for the US Military by supporting on the ground operations in both Germany and Afghanistan.

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Information Systems, Dec 2004 George Washington University BS in Computer Information Systems, May 2003 University of North Texas

EXPERIENCE

10/2013-Present Simpatico Technologies, LLC (clients: EIG, CPP, TSG, HB, Plymouth) - Pittsburgh, PA

SharePoint Consultant, Architect, Admin

- Architected/Deployed multiple SharePoint 2013/0365 farms (2 WFE, 2 App, 3 Search, 2 OWA, 1 Workflow)
- Developed migration strategy to upgrade clients from SharePoint on-premise to SharePoint Online
- Migrated multiple clients from SharePoint 2007/2010/2013/2016 to SharePoint 2016/0365
- Lead multiple SharePoint discovery projects to document and analyze current configuration aliments/bottlenecks
- Worked within client's various business units to gather and translate current business processes into requirements
- Worked with client to help mitigate Microsoft Access to SharePoint 2010 bulk update performance issues
- Configured SharePoint service applications, app model, distributed cache, user profile sync
- Built out hardware specifications to include clustered SQL servers and an F5 load balancer
- Successfully troubleshot SharePoint configuration issues including web app latency issues
- Recommended Microsoft best practices for client's infrastructure and configuration
- Worked with internal Solution Architects and the create/validate Statement of Work documents
- Built custom site templates, InfoPath forms, and multi-stage advanced workflows
- Deployed K2 Blackpearl with SharePoint 2013; created three complex K2 solutions w/ SmartForms & Workflow
- Built multiple solutions using SP Client Object Model, C#, jQuery, Rest API, JavaScript
- Created Nintex forms w/ dynamic fields, conditional display areas, & data validation
- Utilized Nintex Workflow SDK to develop custom actions, inline functions, and web services
- Migrated 2,000 GB of site collection user data, custom content types, custom solutions, and workflows

03/2012-10/2013 1099 Contractor (clients: AES, DOE, Siemens, US Army) - PA, VA, SC, Germany

SharePoint Architect, Developer, Admin

- Architected multiple SharePoint 2010 farms, assisted in development and administration activities
- Developed various solutions (web parts, workflows) to extend OOTB SharePoint using Visual Studio 2012
- Utilized multiple third-party tools (K2, Nintex, Metalogix, and DocAve) in depth for migration/admin/workflow
- Installed and configured MS Server 2008 R2, SharePoint 2010 Enterprise, and SQL Server 2008
- Created 4 custom visual web parts for O365; video WP using Silverlight, Q/A WP, How-to WP, & FAQ WP
- Developed 6+ custom features using Visual Studio and multiple custom visual web parts
- Developed gift donation application using Workflow Foundation to gather approvals via Digital Signatures
- Created 8+ distinct sites for the Marine Corp Museum with custom Web Part Pages and UX
- Created multiple workflows (machine state & sequential), custom Content types, custom web parts
- Migrated client on SP 2007 environment including 500 GB of content to SharePoint 2010
- Helped less experienced SharePoint personnel by assisting them and educating them on best practices
- Utilized jQuery to visually manipulate SharePoint as well as to change native functionality
- Created complex KPI's to assist management with dashboard metrics on already populated SP lists

Shawn Selway

PITTSBURGH, PA | 412.427.7599 SSELWAY@GMAIL.COM

10/2011-03/2012 Tkacz Engineering, LLC (client: US Armed Forces) - Kabul, Afghanistan

SharePoint / C#.NET Developer

- Utilized .NET 4.0, C#, AJAX, JAVASCRIPT, IIS 7, SQL Server 2008 R2
- Built a custom web application in support of Armed Contractor Oversight Directorate
- Re-Architected existing Access database and Excel to SQL Server 2008 with a custom web front end
- Developed data migration and conversion plans for system upgrade
- Converted multiple existing forms & reports so that data entry and views can be done via a web front end
- Recommended policy structures regarding new database systems and security modeling
- Developed database admin procedures, audits, modifies, and amends data in systems
- Created custom SQL Server databases, tables, views and stored procedures in support of this project
- Gave white board meetings and briefings to stakeholders and O-4+ and higher military officers

03/2011-10/2011 ResolvIT (client: College Board) - Reston, VA

SharePoint Architect / Developer / Consultant

- Utilized the SharePoint API to extend web app functionality when OOTB options didn't suffice
- Languages used: C#.NET, AJAX, JQUERY, JAVASCRIPT, T-SQL
- Designed, built, and packaged multiple web parts, features, workflows, and application pages
- Supported and operated multiple SharePoint farms (DEV, QA, Production) with 2500 users
- Troubleshot SharePoint configuration issues and web app latency issues
- Played pivotal role in the migration strategy to move from legacy portal to SharePoint 2010
- Utilized InfoPath to create multiple business forms to suit Stakeholders processes
- Designed, installed, and configured Remote BLOB storage for offloading large video files
- Identified key metadata and developed search scopes, keywords, synonyms, and best bets
- Created custom site definitions, content types, workflows, and UML diagrams

10/2010-02/2011 Software Solutions (client: H.J. Heinz Company) - Pittsburgh, PA

Sr SharePoint Developer / Admin

- Led complex portal and application architecture, design and development
- Architected (3) three multi-server SharePoint 2010 farm configurations
- Interacted with various business unit stakeholders and created the baseline template
- Deployed & maintained SharePoint solutions into both development and production
- Utilized the SharePoint object model to extend functionality (ASP.NET 3.5, C#.NET, and AJAX)
- Created custom web parts to interface with SSRS, Business Connectivity Services, & 3rd party tools
- Created custom site definitions, reusable dynamic workflows, and enterprise content types
- Managed three off shore individuals to leverage cost-savings benefits of a 24/7 work flow

11/2009-10/2010 Objective Paradigm (client: Dell Consulting) - Pittsburgh, PA

SharePoint Developer / Admin

- Lead architect and developer on two (2) SharePoint 2010 deployments & 9 MOSS 2007 farms
- Built numerous SharePoint web parts using C#.NET, AJAX & Silverlight 3.0
- Created custom site definitions for use in UI changes for various business units
- Led complex portal and application architecture, design and development consulting engagements
- Architected multi server MOSS/SharePoint farm configurations from two to eight servers
- Utilized SharePoint Designer and Visual Studio to create dynamic workflows to improve business processes
- Developed, tested, and refined applications to meet client's expectations
- Promoted the adoption of best practices within the Dell software collaboration team
- Developed strong customer relationship skills and abilities to interface with management
- Led white board sessions with new clientele who were unfamiliar with SharePoint's capabilities

Shawn Selway

PITTSBURGH, PA | 412.427.7599 SSELWAY@GMAIL.COM

12/2008-11/2009 General Dynamics (client: US Army) - Stuttgart, Germany

SharePoint Developer

- Developed SP Web Part's using C#, Silverlight 2.0, and the SharePoint object model
- Created custom lists that take advantage of conditional workflows using SharePoint Designer
- Used Visual Studio 2008 to create a SharePoint fly-out window that detailed tips of the week
- Interfaced with client on a weekly basis to insure project was being delivered per their requirements and on time
- Earned Security+ and ITIL certifications as required by the contract

05/2008-12/2008 Integrated Secure (client: National Geospatial Agency) - Vienna, VA

Team Lead Software Engineer

- Led the Java migration effort from Vignette Portal to Weblogic 10
- Developed new java-based solutions using Hibernate, Spring, Java EE, & AJAX
- Developed new Java Portlets to restore previous Vignette portal functionality
- Assisted in the restructure of antiquated development environment by leveraging 3rd party tools

12/2006-04/2008 Lockheed Martin (client: FBI) - Herndon, VA

Senior Software Engineer

- JAVA/J2EE, JSF, Web Application & Portal Development, AJAX
- Spring MVC Framework and utilized Dependency Injection (DI)
- Utilized Eclipse IDE, IBM Clearcase & Rational Functional Tester

09/2004-12/2006 Northrop Grumman (client: US Air Force) - Ramstein AFB, Germany

Software Engineer / Junior SharePoint Developer

- Developed web-based enterprise apps using VB/C#.NET, SQL SERVER, SharePoint Portal Services, WSS
- Utilized MS Visual Studio .NET 2003/2005 & SQL Server 2000/2005
- Developed Relational Databases to support various web applications
- Developed web based enterprise-wide applications for NIPR & SIPR
- Awarded monetary performance award for outstanding performance

10/2003-09/2004 Maximus (client: US Army) - Alexandria, VA

Web Application Developer

J2EE, JAVA, JSP, XML, SQL, HTML Development; Created web-based applications with Oracle 9i backend

01/2000-11/2002 Pacific Gateway Exchange - Dallas, TX

Senior Web Developer

Developed JAVA APPLETS, HTML, XML; Installed, created, and maintained Novell LAN internet & intranet web portals

09/1996-12/1999 Front Page Productions - Burbank, CA

Web Developer

Developed 20+ corporate websites using HTML, PERL, & Adobe Photoshop, java applets, Perl scripts

SKILLSET & MISC

Technology:

SharePoint 2007-2016, O365/SharePoint Online, Nintex, K2, Workflows, PowerShell Scripting, InfoPath Forms, SharePoint COM, ASP.NET, C#, VB.NET, Rest, HTML, CSS, XML, XSL, JavaScript, jQuery

Applications:

MS Visual Studio 2015/13/10/08, SharePoint Designer 2013/10/07, TFS, IIS 7.0, SQL MGR

Certifications:

Security +, ITIL v3